<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>James O&#39;Keefe | Xiyang Wu</title>
    <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/author/james-okeefe/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/author/james-okeefe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>James O&#39;Keefe</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 02:06:07 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/images/icon_hu246a7c5ca50c5215763d04ff4b959e84_299833_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>James O&#39;Keefe</title>
      <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/author/james-okeefe/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>BARK-COVID: An XGBoost Model to Predict Hospitalization at time of COVID-19 Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication/bark_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 02:06:07 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication/bark_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project intends to develop a prediction model with machine learning methods for COVID-19 diagnosis. The model reads patients&#39; clinical history, bio-medical measurements and physical features and make binary classification that predicts 30-day hospital admission for COVID-19 patients. The baseline methods include ElasticNet, Gaussian Naive Bayes Classifier and Logistic Regression. The prediction is evaluated by several metrics based on the confusion matrix. The final prediction model achieves an accuracy over 80%. My responsibility in this project covers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze and filter clinical history, bio-medical testing and physical features in raw datasets, impute missing values via iterativeimputer, establish 5 folder training and testing dataset for prediction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement several machine learning models, including ElasticNet, Gaussian Naive Bayes Classifier, Logistic Regression and XGBoost to predict 30-day hospital admission for COVID-19 patients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze and visualize prediction results generated by each model, compared the prediction with actual 30-day admission records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
