<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2 | Xiyang Wu</title>
    <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication-type/2/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication-type/2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 02:06:07 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/images/icon_hu246a7c5ca50c5215763d04ff4b959e84_299833_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>2</title>
      <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication-type/2/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>BARK-COVID: An XGBoost Model to Predict Hospitalization at time of COVID-19 Diagnosis</title>
      <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication/bark_2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 02:06:07 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication/bark_2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project intends to develop a prediction model with machine learning methods for COVID-19 diagnosis. The model reads patients&#39; clinical history, bio-medical measurements and physical features and make binary classification that predicts 30-day hospital admission for COVID-19 patients. The baseline methods include ElasticNet, Gaussian Naive Bayes Classifier and Logistic Regression. The prediction is evaluated by several metrics based on the confusion matrix. The final prediction model achieves an accuracy over 80%. My responsibility in this project covers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze and filter clinical history, bio-medical testing and physical features in raw datasets, impute missing values via iterativeimputer, establish 5 folder training and testing dataset for prediction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement several machine learning models, including ElasticNet, Gaussian Naive Bayes Classifier, Logistic Regression and XGBoost to predict 30-day hospital admission for COVID-19 patients&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analyze and visualize prediction results generated by each model, compared the prediction with actual 30-day admission records&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online defects detection method for gearboxcover based on the four-source photometric stereo method</title>
      <link>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication/liu-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 16:23:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://wuxiyang1996.github.io/publication/liu-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-photometric-stereo-method-is-effective-in-online-inspection-tasks-but-its-performance-could-be-negatively-affected-by-the-spatial-deviation-in-raw-image-which-necessarily-exists-in-the-online-inspection-environment-this-article-presents-an-online-scratch-detection-method-based-on-the-four-source-photometric-stereo-method-considering-the-size-of-the-component-the-system-divides-the-inspection-process-into-several-locations-and-generates-the-standard-template-covering-the-whole-component-beforehand-once-the-component-approaches-one-of-the-presupposed-locations-lights-from-different-directions-turn-on-successively-and-the-inspection-system-acquires-images-under-dim-lateral-lights-after-acquisition-the-system-compensates-the-images-acquired-for-their-spatial-deviation-and-coordinates-them-on-the-standard-template-after-coordination-the-system-extracts-the-inspection-region-in-the-coordinated-images-generates-the-curvature-image-with-the-photometric-stereo-method-and-detects-scratches-in-the-curvature-image-two-experiments-are-designed-to-verify-the-feasibility-of-the-inspection-method-and-evaluate-the-systems-performance-in-the-online-inspection-environment-according-to-the-result-the-systems-performance-meets-the-accuracy-requirements-which-verifies-the-feasibility-of-this-inspection-method&#34;&gt;The photometric stereo method is effective in online inspection tasks, but its performance could be negatively affected by the spatial deviation in raw image, which necessarily exists in the online inspection environment. This article presents an online scratch detection method based on the four-source photometric stereo method. Considering the size of the component, the system divides the inspection process into several locations and generates the standard template covering the whole component beforehand. Once the component approaches one of the presupposed locations, lights from different directions turn on successively and the inspection system acquires images under dim lateral lights. After acquisition, the system compensates the images acquired for their spatial deviation, and coordinates them on the standard template. After coordination, the system extracts the inspection region in the coordinated images, generates the curvature image with the photometric stereo method and detects scratches in the curvature image. Two experiments are designed to verify the feasibility of the inspection method and evaluate the system&amp;rsquo;s performance in the online inspection environment. According to the result, the system&amp;rsquo;s performance meets the accuracy requirements, which verifies the feasibility of this inspection method.&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
